## Chia-Hsiang Kao

★ Homepage

☑ Primary

♠ ChiaHsiang0326

## **Research Interests**

My goal is to develop robust and interpretable machine learning algorithms and systems that operate reliably even under challenging conditions. Along with my research goals, I am interested in model robustness, unbiased and generalized representation learning, explainable AI, and healthcare applications.

#### Education

## National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University (NYCU)

Taipei, Taiwan

Doctor of Medicine

Aug. 2015 - Jun. 2022

- Overall GPA: 3.81/4.0, Major GPA: 3.82/4.0, CS-related GPA: 3.90/4.0

PS: National Yang Ming University (NYMU) and National Chiao Tung University merged in 2021. I originally studied in NYMU.

PS: In Taiwan, high school students can be directly admitted to medical schools without Bachelor's degree.

## **Publications**

• MAML Is a Noisy Contrastive Learner in Classification | paper | poster |

Chia-Hsiang Kao, Wei-Chen Chiu, and Pin-Yu Chen

## [ICLR'22, poster] [NeurIPS'21 workshop, oral presentation]

- Proved that MAML belongs to supervised contrastive learning.
- Proposed a zeroing trick that significantly improves the convergence of MAML.
- Demystifying T1-MRI to FDG<sup>18</sup>-PET Image Translation via Representational Similarity | paper |

Chia-Hsiang Kao, Yong-Sheng Chen, Li-Fen Chen, and Wei-Chen Chiu

### [MICCAI'21, oral presentation]

- Hypothesized and verified that medical image translation models implicitly segment brain tissue types and identify brain regions.
- Unravelling the Spatio-Temporal Neurodynamics of Rhythm Encoding-Reproduction Networks by a Novel fMRI Autoencoder | paper |

Chia-Hsiang Kao, Ching-Ju Yang, Li-Kai Cheng, Hsin-Yen Yu, Yong-Sheng Chen, Jen-Chuen Hsieh, and Li-Fen Chen [NER'19 (International IEEE/EMBS Conference on Neural Engineering), poster]

- Proposed a novel autoencoder to untangle the spatio-temporal patterns of neurodynamics.
- Identified the rhythm encoding-reproduction networks of the brain.

## **Research Experiences**

## Enriched Vision Applications Lab, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Research Student

Sep. 2020 - Sep. 2021

- Advisor: Professor Wei-Chen Chiu and MIT-IBM Watson AI Lab Researcher Pin-Yu Chen.
- Proved that MAML is a supervised contrastive learning algorithm.
- Studied theories of self-supervised learning and adversarial learning.

# Brain Mapping Laboratory, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University Research Student

Taipei, Taiwan

Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2020

• Advisor: Professor <u>Li-Fen Chen</u>.

- Utilized explainable AI tools to understand the inner behavior of image translation models.
- Analyzed fMRI, MRI, and CT data and built various predictive models.

#### Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica

Taipei, Taiwan

Research Intern

Jun. 2017 - Sep. 2017

• Advisor: Professor Meng-Chang Chen.

• Analyzed air quality data and built air pollution predictive models.

## **Clinical Experiences**

#### Taipei Veteran General Hospital

Taipei, Taiwan

Medical Intern Jan. 2022 - Jun. 2022

• Served as a second-year intern doctor in Internal Medicine, Surgery, ICU, Emergency Medicine, OB/GYN, etc. I was responsible for the primary care of the inpatient in those departments.

Chi Mei Medical Center Tainai, Taiwan

Medical Intern Nov. 2021 - Dec. 2021

• Served as an intern doctor in Internal Medicine and Emergency Medicine.

#### Taipei Veteran General Hospital

Taipei, Taiwan

Medical Intern

Oct. 2019 - Sep. 2020

• Served as a first-year intern doctor in Internal Medicine, Surgery, Radiology, Pediatrics, OB/GYN, Family Medicine, etc. I was responsible for the primary care of the inpatient in those departments.

## Scholarships, Honors, and Services

| • Reviewer, AutoML′22   | Apr. 2022 |
|---|-----------|
| o Junior Reviewer, NeurIPS'21 Workshop  | Oct. 2021 |
| • Student Travel Award, MICCAI'21: To first author student with the highest scoring.                  | Jun. 2021 |
| <ul> <li>College Student Research Scholarships, Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan</li> </ul> | Jul. 2020 |
| <ul> <li>College Student Research Scholarships, Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan</li> </ul> | Jul. 2018 |
| • Summer Research Scholarships, National Health Research Institutes, Taiwan                           | Jul. 2018 |

## Skills and Others

**Languages** Mandarin (Native)

English (Fluent, TOEFL: 106/120)

**Programming** Python (PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, Scikit-learn)

MATLAB

**JAVA** 

**Interests** Jogging and Writing [▶ Medium]